# Interview Playbook

Name:_	Nicholas Garrett	
--------	------------------	--

# **Position Listing**

The position I am using for this playbook is a Security Consultant for Microsoft. The job application page describes this position as an opportunity to help others while assisting in ensuring that teams in mainly Germany are operating in a system-secure environment.

Under the section of Qualifications, it lists:

- Technical knowledge of Microsoft security and identity technologies, such as Active Directory, Azure Active Directory, Microsoft Defender ATP, Azure ATP, Azure Security Center and Azure Sentinel.
- Knowledge of Cybersecurity and Advanced Persistent Threat (APT).
- Credential Theft Mitigation recommended practices.
- Knowledge of Security Assessments and Reviews.
- Knowledge of security, threat modeling, incident response and recovery techniques.
- Knowledge of Hybrid Cloud and Workload Security configurations and practices.
- Ability to design, create and deliver to solution frameworks
- Knowledge of Security Standards, Policies and Governance frameworks
- Experience giving presentations to executive audiences and explaining the benefits of the Microsoft security platform
- Knowledge of competitive security technologies
- Open-source software experience is a plus
- Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)

This is a travel-heavy position, so it is recommended that only those willing to travel regularly apply.

FINALIZED Cover Letter

December 15, 2021

Dear Hiring Manager,

I would like to apply for the Cybersecurity Research position shown on the INL website. I understand that the INL works with cyber-operations and has an entire department dedicated to the cyber field and hope to be considered.

I would like to address in some ways that I could be an asset to Microsoft's cybersecurity team. I have taken an introduction to cybersecurity course, so I have a base of cybersecurity knowledge. In this course, for the semester project, I developed a software program that could scan a target computer system for some simple vulnerabilities an attacker may use. In the course of this project, I learned some of the actual mechanics and systems used in vulnerability scanners, including port scanning, package sniffing, password cracking, and the collection of system information for use in a more targeted attack.

I am currently working on my Bachelor of Science dual major in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, with a certification in Cybersecurity. The BS in Computer Science and Cybersecurity certificate are expected to be completed post the Spring 2022 semester.

In addition to my academic studies, I also practice Judo as a means to improve and develop my personal discipline and focus in my studies. Judo and school have taught me how to put in the work to achieve my goals and to not lose sight of the end goal.

If you feel I am a good fit for this position or another position in your organization, I would greatly appreciate the opportunity to speak with you further regarding my qualities and accomplishments.

Thank you for your consideration,

Nicholas Garrett

Garrnic3@isu.edu

## **Nick Garrett**

6975 N 6000 W Rexburg, ID 83440 \*United States Citizen

(208)-297-4176

garrnic3@isu.edu

## **Employment:**

## Internship: Idaho National Laboratory Cybercore Intern (June-August 2019)

- Helped teach children in the Cybercore Intigration Center-University of Idaho Cyber Summer Camp, where High-school aged children were taught introduction to computers and cybersecurity.
- Helped to build the CAT5 network they performed network attacks over, which consisted of setting up and connecting about 20 network switches.

#### Internship: Web Programming for Interfuse LLC (May 10, 2021 - August 13,2021)

- Developed websites over the summer of 2021 in Javascript using the Vercel system.
- Wrote a full frontend for what will become the Interfuse LLC business webpage.

#### CURM research project: (August 21, 2021 - present)

Currently tasked with building a mathematical model to analyze disease transmission in more realistic settings than current
equations provide.

Little Lemhi Scout Camp staff: (June - August, 2015-2019)

- Taught Archery, Pioneering, Nature, Geocaching, Orienteering, and Mammals Merit Badges to Boy Scouts.
- Had to learn how to teach scouts about the topics listed above, as well as constantly strive to best personify the Scout Oath and Law even when the younger Scouts were not present.

## **Education and Skills:**

Idaho State University: Dual Major with Certification

---3.2 GPA (on 4.0 scale)

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science degree expected May 2022
Applied Mathematics, Bachelor of Science degree expected May 2023
Certificate in Cybersecurity, Minor in Cybersecurity expected May 2022

Familiar computer programming/scripting languages and Software systems:

Python, C, C++, Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, XML, MATLAB and ARM.

Repository for code samples:

https://github.com/codemaxx1/Code Example.git

Vercel, Material UI, JMP 15, PyCharm, IntelliJ, DevC++, TexWorks, Visual Studio Code

## Achievements:

## Academic Decathlon (2016 - 2019)

- Nationals Online Individual Participant: Gold Medal Award in Science.
- Awarded at State: 8 Medals, and 1st Place Overall.
- Put in over 1000 hours of study with specialization in nuclear science, infectious diseases, and optics,

## Judo (2019 - present)

• Brown Belt (12/2/2021)

## Boy Scouts of America (2012 - 2019)

- Eagle Scout, (2014),
  - A after earning the Eagle rank, continued and earned 21 Eagle Palm awards for continued progress in Scouting
- Earned 97 Merit Badges while in the Boy Scouts, each taking on average 5-6 hours each, with some taking 12+ hours
- BSA Unit Senior Patrol Leader (2013-2014)

Learned how to lead other Scouts in my peer group in a direction and to resolve when opinions conflicted

## Service:

Little Lemhi Boy-Scout Camp (June – August, 2015- 2019)

• Served as Staff and Counselor in Training (unpaid) for 4 years (See section under "Employment")

#### Science Camp (2013 - 2015)

Science camp was a summer program that formed to allow middle school students to receive an in-depth, hands-on, science experience for one week in the summer.

- Solicited local business owners to raise funds for Science Camp and raised approximately \$1500 each year in funds to run Science Camp
- Science Camp Founder and Director

# List of 5 Potential Interview Questions You May Be Asked

Question: "What type of experience do you have in cybersecurity?"

Answer: "I have a certification in cybersecurity from Idaho State University, and I have done some work in building a computer system vulnerability scanner."

Question: "What made you want to come to Microsoft for this position?"

Answer: "As I am sure you know, Microsoft is a very large organization. Because it is so large, I feel that the security department must be among the best to maintain proper security for such an important security target."

Question: "What made you decide on cybersecurity as a profession?"

Answer: "I was told about cybersecurity by a family friend who had explained it to me was as a jack of all trades in computer science. Through cybersecurity, I would have to—or rather get to—learn everything about computers."

Question: "What is your favorite operating system, and why?"

Answer: "I suppose there are two answers: Windows and Linux. Windows I prefer for the general day-to-day activities: web-surfing and browsing. Though I prefer Linux more for programming."

Question: "If you had your choice to either work in a physical location or remotely, which would you choose?"

Answer: "Personally, remote work might be more convenient, but having a physical location is better for actually interacting with coworkers. So, I would have to choose a physical location."

List of 5 Potential Technical Questions Related to the Position You Are Pursuing

"Please describe how one may cause a buffer overflow to occur."

"Suppose you have the ability to control the input for a program, what type of vulnerability may you exploit?"

"Could you describe the process of compiling and executing a C program?"

"What threats exist in opensource code?"

"Please describe the main components of an exploit probe."

# List of 5 Potential Questions YOU May Ask the Interviewer(s)

No answers required here.

## Three Personal References

- 1. Xiao (Jessica) Xie, <a href="mailto:xiexia2@isu.edu">xiexia2@isu.edu</a>, and I have known each other for a number of years. First, she taught me in a Linear Algebra class, then was the advisor for a mathematics competition group I was in, and is currently a faculty advisor to an undergraduate research project I am a part of.
- 2. Sami Tadehara, <a href="mailto:samitadehara@isu.edu">samitadehara@isu.edu</a>, is my Judo instructor. Sami sensei and I have known each other for a number of years, though he has come to know me much better in the past year.
- 3. Jamie Hymas, 208-201-0022, is a personal and family friend of mine. We have lived in the same community my whole life, so Jamie has actually seen me grow up, and thus knows me better than most.

Salary Expectations:

Salary Expectation: \$98,989

Location of choice: Austin, Texas